Finding Aid for the Avery Leiserson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Writings by others – articles and reprints
  - Miller, Nicholas, “Pluralism and Social Choice” paper presented at the Annual Meeting of the American Political Science Association, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Mitnik, Barry M. “ A Typology of Conceptions of the Public Interest” reprinted from Administration and Society, Vol. 8, No. 1, May 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Morgenthau, Hans J. “Ethics and Politics”; “World Politics in the Mid-Twentieth Century” reprinted from The Review of Politics, Vol. 10, No. 2, April, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Morris-Jones, W. H. “ Dominance and Disssent: Their Inter-relations in the Indian party system” reprinted from Government and Opposition Journal, Vol., No. 4 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Moynihan, Daniel P. “Imperial Government” in Commentary, June, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Nandy, Ashis “ The Culture of Indian Politics: A Stock Taking” reprinted from The Journal of Asian Studies, Vol. XXX, No. 1, November 1970; “The Making and Unmaking of Political Cultures in India” reprinted from Daedalus, Journal of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Winter 1973; “The Non-Paradigmatic Crisis of Indian Psychology: Reflections on a Recipient Culture of Science” reprinted from the Indian Journal of Psychology, Vol. 49, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Nasr, Nafhat “Dual Executive Leadership in Lebarnon” reprint from Journal of Arab Affairs, Vol. 4, No. 1, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Nathan, Robert R. “ A National Wage Policy for 1947: CIO’s Program for Wage Increases” (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Neumann, Sigmund “Conservatism: New and Old” foreword reprinted from Germany’s New Conservatism, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Nicholls, William H. “Social Biases and Recent Theories of Competition” reprinted from The Quarterly Journal of Economics”, Vol. 58, No. 1, November, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Ogden, Daniel M., Jr. “ The Politics of Conservation in the West, 1953 -54” reprint from Research Studies of the State College of Washington,Vol. XXIII, No. 1, March, 1955 with accompanying letter dated, April 13, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Orren, Gary R. “ The Changing Styles of American Party Politics”;”Pocketbook Politics” in The Public Interest (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Prasad, R.C. “ The Indian Political Scientist: His Dilemmas and Responsibilities” reprinted from Political Scientist, Jan.- June 1965, with accompanying letter dated, May 2, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Quinn, Robert W., M.D. “Family Planning: Definition and Purpose” reprinted from The Southern Medical Bulletin, Bulletin of the Southern Medical Association, Vol. 55, No. 4, December 1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Ranney, Austin “ The Line of the Peas: The Impact of the McGovern-Fraser Commission’s Reforms”; “Recent Changes in the Presidential Nominating Process” The Key Reporter Summer 1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Ranney, Austin and Berdecio, Marion Davis “ Activities of the Committee on Governmental and Legal Processes, 1964 - 72 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Rasmussen, Jorgen S. “Party Discipline in War- Time: The Downfall of the Chamberlain Government” reprint from the Journal of Politics, Vol. 32, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Riesman, David. “ Some Observations on Community Plans and Utopia” reprinted from the Yale Law Journal, December 1947 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Rudolph, Lloyd I. and Rudolph, Susanne Hoeber “ New Era for India: the Fourth General Election,” from Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, Feb. 1968; “ Jaipur Notes # 3” January 7, 1976; “Education and Politics Conference” transcript, New Delhi (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Rustow, Dankwart A. “ Agreement, Dissent, and Democratic Fundamentals” (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Schlesinger, Joseph A. “ The Structure of Competition for Office in the American States” reprinted from Behavioral Science, Vol. 5, No. 3, July 1960; Sharma, K.D. and Sudarshan, Malik (Miss) “ Need for Science Policy (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - In India “ script for radio talk on July 5, 1967 in the AIR programme “Spot Light” (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Sheth, D. L. “ Structure of Indian Radicalism” reprinted from Economic and Political Weekly, Vol. X, Nos. 5 – 7, Annual Number, February 1975 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Shklar, Judith N. “Redeeming American Political Theory” reprinted from American Political Science Review, Vol. 85, No. 1, March 1991 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Simon, Herbert A. “Notes on the Observation and Measurement of Political Power” in the Journal of Politics, Vol. 15, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Somit, Albert “ Reports of Two Key SSRC Committees: Back to the Board?” (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Stocking, George W. “Saving Free Enterprise from its Friends” reprinted The Southern Economic Journal, Vol. XIX, No. 4, April, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Tanenhaus, Joseph “Organized Labor’s Political Spending: the Law and Its Consequences” in The Journal of Politics, Vol. 16, 1954; “ Supreme Court Attitudes Toward Federal Administrative Agencies 1947 -1956: An Application of Social Science Methods to the Study of the Judicial Process” reprinted from the Vanderbilt Law Review, Vol. 14, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Toulmin, Stephen “From Form to Function: Philosophy and History of Science in the 1950’s and Now” (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Truman, David B. “ Disillusion and Regeneration: The Quest for a Discipline” reprinted from The American Political Science Review, Vol. LIX, No. 4, December, 1965; “The Committee on Political Behavior, 1949 - 63: An Introduction (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Waldo, Dwight “ Education for Public Administration in the Seventies” prepared for meetings of the National Association of Schools of Public Affairs and Administration, first draft, January 1974 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Wahlke, John C. “Pre-Behavioralism in Political Science” Presidential Address, American Political Science Association, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Weinberg, Alvin M. “How Can Man Live with Fission?”, April 11, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Weinberg, Steven “A Designer Universe” in The New York Review of Books, Oct. 21, 1999 based on a talk given in April 1999 at the Conference on Cosmic Design of the American Association for the Advancement of Science in Washington, D.C. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Westfeldt, Wallace “ Settling a Sit-in” and “A Report on Nashville” reports prepared for the Nashville Community Relations Conference with accompanying letter from Alma Gault, Chairman of the NCRC, dated, November 15,1960 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Worley, James S. “Industrial Research and the New Competition” reprint from the Journal of Political Economy, Vol. LXIX, April 1961 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - “Memorandum on the Organization of the Du Pont Company, April, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - “The Structure of the Soviet Foreign Propaganda Organization” (A summary) (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - “Program for Improving the Conduct of Government Affairs”, August 14, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Writings by others – book reviews
  - Adams, Walter “A Blueprint for Technocracy” review of The New Industrial State by John Kenneth Galbraith, in Science, Vol. 157, August 1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Albritton, Claude “A Call for Unity” review of Science: Growth and Change by Henry W. Menard, 1971 in Science, Vol. 176, May 1972 Almond, Gabriel A. review of Charles E. Merriam and the Study of Politics by Barry D. Karl, 1974 in American Political Science Review, Vol. 70,1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Anna n, Noel “Dean of the Cold War” review of Acheson: The Secretary of State Who Created the American World by James Chace in The New York Review of Books, Nov. 19, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Bernsstein, Richard “ A Score Card for Vietnam: It was Johnson 1, Nixon (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - O” review of Vietnam: The Necessary War by Michael Lind, 1999 in The New York Times, Oct. 20, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Brock, David “Personal Accounts” reviews of Inside the National Security Council by Constantine C. Menges and Perilous Statecraft: An Insider’s Account of the Iran Contra Affair by Michael A. Ledeen in Commentary, February, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Buruma, Ian “The Last Laugh” review of Thy Hand, Great Anarch! India, 1921 – 1952 by Nirad C. Chaudhuri in New York Review of Books, Dec. 8, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Cottrell, Robert “ Europe: So Far, It Flies” review of This Blessed Plot: Britain and Europe from Churchill to Blair by Hugo Young and Redrawing the Map of Europe by Michael Emerson in the New York Review of Books, April 8, 1999 and “A Rite of Passage for the European Union” by Anne Swardson in the Washington Post National Weekly Edition, March 29, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Davies, Norman “The Misunderstood War” review of A World at Arms: A Global History of World War II by Gerhard L. Weinberg in The New York Review of Books, June 9, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - De Beer, Sir Gavin “ The World of an Evolutionist” review of This View of Life by George Gaylord Simpson in Science, Vol.143, March 20, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - De Grazia, Alfred review of Power and Society: A Framework for Political Inquiry by Harold D. Lasswell and Abraham Kaplan in The University of Chicago Law Review, Vol. 19, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Draper, Theodore “Rewriting the Iran – Contra Story” reviews of Men of Zeal: A Candid Inside Story of the Iran – Contra Hearings by Senators William S. Cohen and George J. Mitchell; Guts and Glory: The Rise and Fall of Oliver North by Ben Bradlee, Jr.; The Iranian Triangle: The Untold Story of Israel’s Role in the Iran- Contra Affair by Samuel Segev; Perilous Statecraft: An Insider’s Account of the Iran-Contra Affair by Michael A. Ledeen; Landslide: The Unmaking of the President 1984 – 1988 by Jane Mayer and Doyle McManus in The New York Review of Books, January 19, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Draper, Theodore “The Iran-Contra Secrets” reviews of Turmoil and Triumph: My Years as Secretary of State by George P. Schultz; Undue Process: A Story of How Political Differences Are Turned into Crimes by Elliott Abrams; Fourth Interim Report to Congress by Lawrence E.Walsh, Independent Counsel for Iran/Contra Matters; With Reagan: The Inside Story by Edwin Meese in The New York Review of Books, May 27, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Dworkin, Ronald “What Liberalism Isn’t” review of Social Justice in the Liberal State by Bruce A.Ackerman in The New York Review of Books, Jan. 20, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Epstein, Jason “Is the Party Over” reviews of Friendly Fascism: The New Face of Power in America by Bertram Gross; Crisis Investing: Opportunities and Profits in the Coming Great Depression by Douglas R. Casey in The New York Review of Books, Oct. 23, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Fallows, James “ For Old Times Sake” reviews of Keeping Faith: Memoirs of a President by Jimmy Carter; Crisis: The Last Year of the Carter Presidency by Hamilton Jordan in The New York Review of Books, Dec. 16, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Fallows, James “Reagan: The Fruits of Success” reviews of Gambling with History: Ronald Reagan in the White House by Laurence I. Barrett; Reagan’s Ruling Class: Portraits of the President’s Top One Hundred Officials by Ronald Brownstein and Nina Easton in The New York Review of Books, Oct. 27, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Featherstone, Joseph “The Politics of Education” review of The Revisionist Revised: A Critique of the Radical Attack on the Schools by Diane Ravitch in The New York Times Book Review, June 18, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Ferkiss, Victor “Present Discontents” review of An End to Political Science by Marvin Surkin and Alan Wolfe in Science, Vol 171 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Frady, Marshall “Prophet with Honor” review of Let the Trumpet Sound: the Life of Martin Luther King, Jr. by Stephen B. Oates in The New York Review of Books, Oct. 27, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Geertz, Clifford “Learning with Bruner” review of The Culture of Education by Jerome Bruner in The New York Review of Books, April 10, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Goodell, Rae “The French Connection” review of Scientists in Power by Spencer R. Weart in The New York Times Book Review, August 26, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Graham, George J., Jr. review of Politics, Self, and Society: A Theme and Variations by Heinz Eulau in American Political Science Review, Vol. 81 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Greenberg, David “Richard Hofstadter’s Tradition” review of The American Political Tradition: And the Men Who Made It by Richard Hofstadter in The Atlantic Monthly, November 1998 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Hacker, Andrew “Grand Illusion” review of One Nation, After All by Alan Wolfe; Someone Else’s House: America’s Unfinished Struggle for Integration by Tamar Jacoby; Reaching Beyond Race by Paul M. Sniderman and Edward G. Carmines; Portrait of American Jews: The Last Half of the 20th Century by Samuel C. Heilman; Roberts vs. Texaco: A True Story of Race and Corporate America by Bari-Ellen Roberts and Jack E. White in The New York Review of Books, June 11, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Hacker, Andrew “Up for Grabs” review of The United States in the 1980’s by Peter Duignan and Alvin Rabushka; Setting National Priorities: Agenda for the 1980’s by Joseph A. Pechman; Human Scale by Kirkpatrick Sale; The Third Wave by Alvin Toffler; The Microelectronics Revolution edited by Tom Forester; The 1980’s: Countdown to Armaggeddon by Hal (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Lindsey; A Normal Agenda for the Eighties: Report of the President’s Commision for a National Agenda for the Eighties, U.S. Government Printing Office; Life After ’80: Environmental Choices We Can Live With edited by Kathleen Courrier in The New York Review of Books, April 30, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Hacker, Andrew “ ‘Welfare’ the Future of an Illusion” review of The Economic Illusion: False Choices Between Prosperity and Social Justice by Robert Kuttner; Captitalism and the Welfare State: Dilemmnas of Social Benevolence by Neil Gilbert; Kate Quinton’s Days by Susan Sheehan; Selective Nontreatment of Handicapped Newborns: Moral Dilemmas in Neonatal Medicine by Robert F. Weir; What is a Wife Worth? by Michael H. Minton with Jean Libman Block; Demographic and Socioeconomic Aspects of Aging in the United States, Bureau of the Census, U.S. Department of Commerce; Catholic Social Teaching and the U.S. Economy, US Bishops Ad Hoc Committee, National Catholic News Service in The New York Review of Books, Feb. 28, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Hertzberg, Hendrik “Part of the Solution, Part of the Problem” review of “Democracy is in the Streets” From Port Huron to the Siege of Chicago by James Miller in New York Times Book Review, June 21, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Higham, John “The Pot that Didn’t Melt” review of The Jews in America: Four Centuries of an Uneasy Encounter: A History by Arthur Hertzberg in The New York Review of Books, April 12, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Horowitz, Irving Louis “A Third Way?” review of Whose Keeper? Social Science and Moral Obligation by Alan Wolfe in First Things, May 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Hoebel, Bartley G. “Bases of Motivation and Learning” review of Drives and Reinforcementss: Behavioral Studies of Hypothalmic Functions by James Olds in Science, Vol. 200, May 12, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Johnson, Chalmers “The Moral Equivalent of Defeat” review of The Rise of the Trading State by Richard Rosecrance; The Zero-Sum Solution by Lester C. Thurow in The Atlantic Monthly, December 1985 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Kazin, Alfred “The Father of Us All” review of Waldo Emerson: A Biography by Gay Wilson Allen in The New York Review of Books, Jan. 21, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Kedourie, Elie “The Ironies of Negotiation” review of Camp David: Peacemaking and Politics by William B. Quandt in The New Republic, Sept. 1, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Kempton, Murray “The Wind that Blew in Reagan” review of The New Politics of Inequality by Thomas Byrne Edsall in The New York Review of Books, Feb. 28, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Kerr, Sarah “The Two Faces of Mexico” review of Mexico: Biography of Power: A History of Modern Mexico, 1810 -1996 by Enrique Krauze, trans. by Hank Heifetz in The New York Times Book Review, July 27, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Lemann, Nicholas “Justice for Blacks” reviews of Race, Crime, and the Law by Randall Kennedy; Search and Destroy: African-American Males in the Criminal Justice System by Jerome G. Miller; Malign Neglect: Race, Crime, and Punishment in American by Michael Tonry in The New York Review of Books, March 5, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Leughtenburg, William E. “Preacher of Parasox” review of Reinhold Niebuhr: A Biography by Richard W. Fox in The Atlantic Monthly, January 1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Levin, Harry “The Great Good Place” review of Utopian Thought in the Western World by Frank E. Manuel and Fritzie P. Manuel in The New York Review of Books, March 6, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Lewontin, R.C. “ Darwin, Mendel, and the Mind” review of The Survival of Charles Darwin: A Biography of a Man and an Idea by Ronald W. Clark; The Correspondence of Charles Darwin, Volume I:1821 – 1836 edited by Frederick Burkhardt and Sydney Smith; Past Masters: Mendel by Vitezslav Orel; Past Masters: Lamarck by L. J. Jordanova; Neuronal Man: The Biology of Mind by Jean-Pierre Changeux in The New York Review of Books, October 10, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lewontin, Richard “The Politics of Science” review of Science, Truth, and Democracy by Philip Kitcher; Science, Money, and Politics: Political Triumph and Ethical Erosion by Daniel S. Greenberg; Our Posthuman Future: Consequences of the Biotechnolgy Revolution by Francis Fukuyama in The New York Review of Books, May 9, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lewontin, R.C. “Sex, Lies, and Social Science” review of Science in the Bedroom: A History of Sex Research by Vern L. Bullough; The Social Organization of Sexuality: Sexual Practices in the United States by Edward O. Laumann, John H. Gagnon, Robert T. Michael, and Stuart Michaels; Sex in America: A Definitive Survey by Robert T. Michael; John H. Gagnon, Edward O. Laumann, and Gina Kolata in The New York Review of Books, April 20, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Lund, Michael S. “A Most Popular Conspiracy” review of Policymaking for Social Security by Martha Derthick in The Public Interest (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Mangone, Gerard J. review of Teaching Political Science: A Challenge to Higher Education by Robert H. Connery in The American Academy of Political and Social Science, Vol. 362, Nov. 1965 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - McPherson, James “The Heart of the Matter” review of Slavery and the American West: The Eclipse of Manifest Destiny and the Coming of the Civil War by Michael A. Morrison; Days of Defiance: Sumter, Secession, and the Coming of the Civil War by Maury Klein; Behind the Lines in the Southern Confederacy by Charles W. Ramsdell; The Confederate War by Gary W. Gallagher in The New York Review of Books, October 23,1997 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mirsky, Jonathan “The Never-Ending War” review of Argument Without End: In Search of Answers to the Vietnam Tragedy by Robert S. McNamara, James G. Blight, Robert K. Brigham, Thomas J. Biersteker, and Herbert Y. Schandler; Reporting Vietnam Part One: American Journalism 1959-1969; Part Two: American Journalsim, 1969 -1975, Library of America; American Tragedy: Kennedy, Johnson, and the Origins of the Vietnam War by David Kaiser; Guerrilla Deplomacy: The NLF’s Foreigh Relations and the Viet Nam War BY Robert K. Brigham; Choosing War: the Lost Chance for Peace and the Escalation of War in Vietnam by Fredrik Logevall; Dragon Ascending: Vietnam and the Vietnamese by Henry Kamm; The Secret War Against Hanoi: Kennedy’s and Johnson’s Use of Spies, Saboteurs, and Covert Warriors in North Vietnam by Richard H. Shultz, Jr.; In the Jaws of History by Bui Diem, with David Chanoff; A Better War: The Unexamined Victories and Final Tragedy of America’s Last Years in Vietnam by Lewis Sorley; Vietnam, the Necessary War: A Reinterpretation of America’s Most Disastrous Military Conflict by Michael Lind; America’s War in Vietnam: A Short Narrative History by Larry H. Addington; Memories of a Pure Spring by Duong Thu Huong in The New York Review of Books, May 25, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Moon, J. Donald review of The Descent of Political Theory: The Genealogy of an American Vocation by John G. Gunnel in American Political Science Review, Vol. 88, No. 3, Sept. 1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Morgan, Edmund S. “The Genuine Article” review of Founding Father: Rediscovering George Washington by Richard Brookhiser in The New York Review of Books, June 25, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Morgan, Edmund S. “The Second American Revolution” review of The Radicalism of the American Revolution by Gordon S. Wood (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Morgan, Edmund S. “Popular Fiction” review of A Machine That Would Go of Itself: The Constitution in American Culture by Michael Kammen; Supplement to Max Farrand’s Records of the Federal Converntion of 1787 by James Hutson; Decision in Philadelphia: The Constitutional Convention of 1787 by Christopher Collier and James Lincoln Collier; A More Perfect Union by William Peters; The Founding: A Dramatic Account of the Writing of the Constitution by Fred Barbash; The Genius of the People by Charles L. Mee, Jr.; Peripheries and Center: Constitutional Development in the Extended Politics of the British Empire and the United States, 1607, 1788 by Jack P. Greene; Are We to Be A Nation? The Making of the Constitution by Richard B. Bernstein with Kym S. Rice; Witnesses at the Creation: Hamilton, Madison, Jay and the Constitution by Richard B. Morris; The Forging of the Union, 1781 – 1789 by Richard B. Morris; Novus Ordo Seclorum: The Intellectual Origins of the Constitution by Forrest McDonald; Encyclopedia of the American Constitution by Leonard W. Levy, Kenneth L. Karst, and Dennis J. Mahoney; The Founder’s Constitution by Philip B. Kurland and Ralph Lerner; The Constitution in the Supreme Court: The First Hundred Years, 1789-1888 by David P. Currie; The Enduring Constitution by Jethro K. Lieberman; We Hold These Truths: Understanding the Ideas and Ideals of the Constitution by Mortimer J. Adler; Taking the Constitution Seriously by Walter Berns; The Establishment Clause: Religion and the First Amendment by Leonard W. Levy; The First Liberty: Religion and the American Republic by William Lee Miller in The New Republic, June 29, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Paret, Peter review of Strategy: The Logic of War and Peace by E.N. Luttwak in The New Republic, May 11, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Pindyck, Robert S. “The American Energy Debate” review of Energy Future: Report on th Energy Project at the Harvard Business School by Robert Stobaugh and Daniel Yergin; Energy: The Next Twenty Years by The Ford Foundation Study Group Report in The Public Interest (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Powers, Thomas “How the Bomb was Kept from Hitler” review of German National Socialism and the Quest for Nuclear Power, 1939 – 1949 by Mark Walker, May 1990 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Powers, Thomas “The Unanswered Question” review of Copenhagen a play by Michael Frayn in The New York Review of Books, May 25, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Preston, Julia “Looking Back at the Revolution” review of Blood of Brothers: Life and War in Nicaragua by Stephen Kinzer; Inside Central America: Its People, Politics, and History by Clifford Krauss in The New York Review of Books, July 18, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Rothschild, Emma “The Real Reagan Economy” review of Budget of the United States Government: Fiscal Year 1989; Economic Report of the President, Transmitted to the Congress, February 1988, Together with the Annual Report of the Council of Economic Advisers in The New York Review of Books, June 30, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Ryan, Alan “It Takes All Kinds” review of The Next American Nation: the New Nationalism and the Fourth American Revolution by Michael Lind in The New York Review of Books, Oct. 5, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 19)